Javier Ovalle /

Partner

Practice Area: Litigation

javier.ovalle@ocl.cl

Javier heads the firm's Litigation area. He has focused on multidisciplinary legal counsel, acquiring that skill through a varied professional experience in corporate, tax, judicial, real estate and regulatory matters. He has an intimate understanding of economic sectors such as agroindustry, aquiculture, real estate, education and finance.

WORK HISTORY

1994 - present / Ovalle Consejeros Legales

1989 - 1994 / Cariola y Cía.

1986 - 1989 / Ovalle, Weinstein y Jara.

EXPERIENCE

- Director of agroindustrial, finance, commercial and real estate companies.
- Counsel to trade associations.
- · Board member of schools.
- Negotiation and drafting of legal and commercial terms in mergers and acquisitions of industrial, agroindustrial, agricultural, aquacultural, wholesale and retail, real estate, financial and educational organizations.
- Legal and business consulting to well-known entrepreneurs.
- Corporate dispute resolution.
- Lead counsel in complex civil and commercial lawsuits.
- Representation of interests to domestic and foreign government and multilateral agencies.

EDUCATION

B.A. in Legal and Social Sciences, graduating summa cum laude, University of Chile. Admissions: 1986.

MEMBERSHIPS

- Chilean Bar Association
- Public Freedom Association of Chile

LANGUAGES

Spanish and English